http://www.performance-additives.com/privacy-policy

Technical Reports
PERFORMANCE-ADDITIVES WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICYPerformance Additives respects the confidentiality of your information. We conduct our business in full compliance with applicable laws and regulations on data privacy protection and security, including the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2016 that came into force on 25 May 2018.Privacy StatementPerformance-Additives appreciates the risks associated with the electronic sharing of information. Performance-Additives’s policy includes commercially reasonable precautions for securing any information it obtains from visitors to our website, securing storage locations, and limiting access to gathered information. It is also Performance-Additives’s policy to limit access to our website and network to protect against the spread of computer viruses or other unauthorized foreign programs.Information Collection and SharingWe collect personal information from website visitors on a voluntary basis only. We do not obtain personally identifiable information just by a visitor’s access and use of our site. Some visitors will elect to complete a contact form that does provide us with some confidential information. Visitors submitting a contact form will include their name, title, company, address, phone number, e-mail address, and optional additional information. However, personal information need not be provided in order to use or access our website. If a user elects to provide personally-identifiable data, like that listed above, it is Performance-Additives’s standard practice not to sell, rent, or market that information to any third parties. Personal information volunteered by our visitors is kept in a database on a server located at our corporate headquarters. Access to this database is limited in order to increase security.We use information provided for such purposes as processing and responding to price requests, improving our website and operations, evaluating the needs of our clients, and communicating with visitors regarding products, events, and our business. These efforts may require us to share demographic and statistical information with some of our advertisers, business partners, and support providers. However, it is our policy to not provide personal information along with such data. Further, we will take reasonably appropriate measures to insure any provided information is not offered in a manner that is linked to the source of personally identifiable content.Trade Secret and Confidential InformationOur general contact form also includes a field allowing visitors to tailor the comments or questions submitted via our website. Though we will treat the information provided by a visitor as confidential, and in accordance with the terms of this policy, we ask and suggest that visitors not include trade secret, proprietary, or other business confidential information through this format. We cannot guarantee sufficiently limited access to this information to ensure its status as a trade secret. Instead, we can provide assistance addressing visitors’ confidential information in a more personalized and controlled manner. If you have specific questions relating to details of your business, indicate this to us in a contact form without revealing trade secret or business confidential information. We will follow-up with you in a manner better suited to protecting that information.Some visitors may utilize our website to request price quotes or to place orders with us. These requests or communications may include especially sensitive information. Requests for quotes will be collected and maintained separately from other website information. In the event that a visitor provides confidential business information, including details regarding business operations and products that may be proprietary to our visitor, it is our policy to maintain that information securely on a Performance-Additives server. We will attempt to limit access to such information to certain employees in the company. Such highly confidential information will not be intentionally provided to any third parties, except in the limited circumstances where such disclosure is required by law or to maintain security, or with the visitor’s express consent.Technical InformationOur web server does automatically obtain non-personally-identifiable information from a visitor’s computer when they access our site. This is generally technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect the visitor’s computer to the Internet, and the domain name (or other identifier) of the platform that the visitor uses to access our site. Also collected for technical purposes are the visitor’s operating system, and browser type and version. In some instances, the website analytic software will tabulate the amount of time a user is on our website, the actual pages viewed, the information searched for, and other relevant statistics we use to upgrade and improve our web-based services.Our server will record a website user’s IP address. However, our software does not gather information regarding a visitor’s prior or later web activities, and we will not tabulate data regarding other websites a user may have visited. All tabulations made incorporating an IP address will not be linked to personally identifiable information.The software we use to gather statistical and technical data does not obtain a user’s personally identifiable information. As such, any aggregate-use data prepared by this software does not link a particular visitor to our website in any manner. We will never collect a visitor’s username or password they used to access the Internet or a personal network, nor will we intentionally gather personally identifiable information otherwise stored on a user’s computer or network, except if incorporated or linked to the technical information described herein.Additionally, our server uses cookies to tailor the website experience for repeat visitors. Cookies are packets of data transferred to the hard drive of a visitor’s computer. These remain on the visitor’s system for use in the event the visitor returns to our website. At that time, our server can utilize the information contained in the cookie to manage our site to better fit the visitor’s desired experience. Many websites use cookies, and most computers and Internet browsers allow a user to limit or reject cookies. Electing such limits could change the visitor’s interaction with our website or prevent access altogether. Visitors are free to delete or remove a cookie placed on their system at their own volition.Additional PoliciesNotwithstanding any provision in this policy, we reserve the right to collect, use and disclose personal information in connection with security-related matters or law enforcement investigations, and will comply with requests for such information where required by law.We will take commercially reasonably precautions to protect information obtained from visitors to our website against unauthorized access, use, or transfer.Any website visitor may request in writing that we change or delete any previously provided personally identifiable information. These requests should be made via Performance-Additives’s website.Our site includes links to other websites. We are not responsible for either the content on those sites, their security, or the use of any information provided to them by a visitor. This privacy policy does not extend to those websites.We reserve the right to modify, amend, or change this privacy policy without prior written notice.DISCLAIMERSNOTWITHSTANDING ANY PROVISIONS CONTAINED HEREIN, PERFORMANCE-ADDITIVES HEREBY DISCLAIMS ANY AND ALL LIABILITIES THAT MAYARISE OUT OF OR RELATE TO A VISITOR’S ACCESSING OF OR RELIANCE ON THE INFORMATION CONTAINED ON THIS WEBSITE, OR IN THIS POLICY. INFORMATION PROVIDED ON THIS WEBSITE IS GENERAL IN NATURE AND IS NOT INTENDED TO BE A WARRANTY OF THE SECURITY OR PRIVACY OF PROVIDED OR COLLECTED INFORMATION. THIS WEBSITE DOES NOT CREATE, PERFORMANCE-ADDITIVES EXPRESSLY DENIES, AND ANY VISITOR WAIVES, ANY DUTY OR LEGAL OBLIGATION THAT MAY ARISE OUT OF OR BE IMPOSED BASED ON THE STATEMENTS CONTAINED HEREIN. PERFORMANCE-ADDITIVES DISCLAIMS ANY DUTIES OR OBLIGATIONS TO MAINTAIN THE PRIVACY AND SECURITY OF ANY VISITOR TO THE WEBSITE, ANY INFORMATION PROVIDED, OR DATA COLLECTED, TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW.THOUGH WE WILL MAKE REASONABLE EFFORTS TO ADHERE TO THE POLICIES AND PROCEDURES CONTAINED HEREIN, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE SPECIFIC METHODS FOR SECURING PRIVACY OF PERSONALLY-IDENTIFIABLE OR CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION, PERFORMANCE-ADDITIVES DOES NOT AND CANNOT WARRANT THE CONTINUOUS USE OR EFFECTIVENESS OF SUCH POLICIES AND PROCEDURES.PERFORMANCE-ADDITIVES DISCLAIMS ANY AND ALL LIABILITIES FOR ANY DAMAGES OR LOSSES ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO A VISITOR’S USE OF THE WEBSITE. THIS DISCLAIMER INCLUDES, BUT IS NOT LIMITED TO, DAMAGE OR LOSS (INCLUDING LOST PROFITS) RESULTING FROM THIRD-PARTY ACCESS TO A USER’S SYSTEM OR INFORMATION, REGARDLESS OF WHERE THAT INFORMATION IS STORED; TRANSFER OF ELECTRONIC DATA OF ANY KIND TO A USER’S COMPUTER, NETWORK, SERVER, OR SYSTEM; AND A USER’S ACCESS TO INFORMATION THROUGH OUR WEBSITE.BY ACCESSING OR VISITING THIS WEBSITE, A VISITOR AFFIRMATIVELY DISCLAIMS, DISCHARGES, RELINQUISHES, RELEASES AND WAIVES, ANY AND ALL REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES FROM PERFORMANCE-ADDITIVES THAT MAY ARISE OUT OF OR RELATE TO THE INFORMATION ON THIS WEBSITE, THIS POLICY OR ANY STATEMENTS CONTAINED THEREIN. USE OF THIS WEBSITES CONSTITUTES A WAIVER OF ALL CLAIMS OR CAUSES OF ACTION, WHETHER KNOWN OR UNKNOWN, ACCRUED OR UNACCRUED, AT LAW OR IN EQUITY, ARISING OUT OF OR RELATED TO THE USE OF THIS WEBSITE OR RELIANCE ON ANY INFORMATION CONTAINED HEREIN.
